Hi, everyone! I'm Van Riper and I'm
Adriana Cerundolo.
And, we support the global Google Developer
Group community from the Googleplex
right here in Mountain View California.
We are super excited about DevFest 2014.
I wanna thank you all for joining us
Know that you are part of a global
diverse community people interested in
Google tech, and we hope you make at least
one new friend, today.
This is the third year the GDGs have
been organizing DevFest.
And, these are great opportunities to
learn about, and play with Google
developer tools.
Last year, GDG held 160 DevFest
in 60 countries reaching more than
35,000 developers.
Google technology talks, tutorials, code
labs,
and hackathons were a big part in it.
From GDG cookies,
to dancing, to Star Wars costumes these
events are also incredibly creative and
fun.
These are just a few memories from the
many amazing events that happened all
over the world in 2013.
We look forward to keeping this momentum
going again this year.
I can't wait to see what fun this is.
Please be sure to share your photos on
GPlus with hash tag #GDG
hash tag #DevFest, so we can all follow along.
And, we want to make sure that you have
the best experience possible. We can't do
that without your feedback.
So please be sure to complete the event
survey for after the event.
Thanks for supporting your local GDG and
from your supporting team here in
Mountain View.
Have a fantastic DevFest 2014!