DAVID SINGLETON: We're
right at the beginning
in a new phase in the
miniaturization of technology,
which means that it's
finally possible to make
a powerful computer small
enough to wear comfortably
on your body all day long.
And there's a huge opportunity
to bring rich user experiences
to these devices.
And that's why we're building
Androidwear as our platform
for wearables based on Android.
Androidwear makes it
easy for developers
to reach users on this
new form factor using
precisely the same
tools we're already
familiar with on Android
phones and tablets.
People will be wearing these
small, powerful devices,
so style is important.
And that's why
Androidwear supports
both square and
circular screens.
And we think that there
will be a wide variety
of fashionable designs.
Sensors will help them
understand your context.
So they can provide useful
information when you need it
and help you reach
your fitness goals.
And as the device that
you always have with you,
your watch will also
provide intelligent answers
to spoken questions and
as Dave showed us earlier,
act as your key in a
multi-screen world.
Across the world, people
check their Android phones
an average of 125
times every day.
And that's why we've designed
Androidwear to quickly show
you relevant information
and make sure
you never miss an
important message,
while letting you stay
engaged with the people
that you're actually with.
We do this by working to
understand the context of what
you care about,
while enabling very
brief interactions
with the device.
Here's a live demo
on the LGG watch.
You can see that it has
an Always On display,
than at any given time, it shows
you the most important thing we
for you.
So Jeff, it looks
like your flight
to Brazil for the
World Cup is on time.
I guess you do deserve a
break after this big demo.
And if Jeff wanted
to see more, he
can simply raise his
watch of tap the screen
to switch into
vibrant, full color
that you're already seeing here.
Throughout the day, if Jeff
receives a notification which
buzzes his phone, his watch
will vibrate on his wrist
and show him what's
up at a glance.
So he won't miss an important
message like this one.
Swiping up and
down navigates you
through this stream of cards,
which includes information
from Google Now, apps
running on Jeff's phone,
and apps running directly
on the wearable itself.
And when there's
a page indicator,
Jeff can swipe horizontally
to see more details.
You can see that we've
applied material design here.
The cards float above
beautiful, textured backgrounds.
And just like in your
phone's notification shade,
you can swipe a card away to
remove it from your stream.
Let's take a look
at Jeff's phone.
And that notification
has disappeared.
Back at the watch face,
pressing and holding
lets you choose a different one.
You can see that there's
a broad selection
of analog and digital designs
in a variety of styles
to suit your tastes.
OK, now that we're acquainted
with the overall UI model,
let's see how Androidwear
can work for you.
Imagine that Jeff has just
got up in the morning.
He swipes up and sees the
weather forecast for the day.
His commute's not
looking too bad.
And oh look, Jeff, I guess you
need that package for your trip
to Brazil.
You better not
forget to pick it up.
JEFF: OK, Google.
Remind me to check my
mailbox when I get home.
DAVID SINGLETON: Now If
we can see Jeff's phone
at the same time, you'll
see that this is immediately
synced across.
[APPLAUSE]
DAVID SINGLETON:
And in this case,
his watch was smart enough
to know where home is.
A little later on, as Jeff
is arriving at the office,
his watch vibrates again
with a chat message
from one of the team.
He can see who it's from
and what he's saying, all
without having to fumble
around and get out his phone.
You're watching your
phone stay in sync.
When you swipe away a
notification on the watch,
it disappears from the phone,
as Jeff is showing now.
[APPLAUSE]
It's super convenient.
In the evening, Jeff
is having dinner
with a friend at a restaurant.
If he's unfamiliar with one of
the ingredients on the menu,
he can just say--
JEFF: What is limburger?
DAVID SINGLETON: So it
looks like limburger
or is a type of cheese.
Jeff is lactose
intolerant, so he better
order something different, or
this dinner could go wrong.
And when Jeff receives a phone
call, his watch will vibrate,
and he can see who's
calling at a glance.
It's another one of
Jeff's co-workers.
Now Jeff could get out his phone
to answer, but since he's busy,
he can either swipe to reject
the call from his wrist
or swipe up to choose from one
of these quick SMS replies.
His phone sends the
SMS, and he's done.
[APPLAUSE]
Sometimes you're enjoying
dinner so much that you
want to avoid any
more interruptions.
And for that, you can
set Do Not Disturb
with a single downward swipe
from the top of the screen.
[APPLAUSE]
And now Jeff's watch won't buzz
again until he wants it to.
Later that night,
Jeff arrives home.
Oh, that's right.
Your package is here.
Now that he's at
home, the reminder
that Jeff created this
morning has triggered.
You can also use
Androidwearables
to control other
devices around you.
Let's loosen up
with a bit of music.
JEFF: Play some music.
DAVID SINGLETON: Now
you'll see that Jeff
has music controls on his watch.
[MUSIC - CHROMEO, "JEALOUS (I
AIN'T WITH IT)"]
He can see what song is playing.
He can pause the music or
skip to the next track.
And while it's
playing, the album art
is beautifully displayed
right there on his wrist.
Finally, at the end of the
day, it's time for bed.
JEFF: Set an alarm for 7:00 AM.
DAVID SINGLETON: With glanceable
notifications and quick voice
actions, Androidwear
gives you what
you need right when you need it.
Let's take a closer look at some
of the contextual information
that Androidwear provides
when you're traveling.
So Jeff's about to leave on
that big trip to the World Cup.
It's the morning of his flight.
So his phone is already
displaying relevant information
for his trip.
He can see his flight status
and even show his boarding pass.
His hotel address will be
there when he needs it.
And he knows whether or not
he'll need to pack an umbrella.
It does look like it's going
to rain in Brazil on Friday.
Once he's in Brazil,
Androidwear continues
to give him useful,
timely information
at a glance, whether
it's his restaurant
reservation, the
time back at home
so he knows when
to call as family,
or the local bus schedule.
And while he's walking
around the city,
Jeff can see how many
steps he's taken today,
along with a step count
history for the week.
On devices that
support it, he can even
check his heart
rate after a jog.
[APPLAUSE]
So we've shown you
what Androidwear
can do out of the box.
We're even more excited
to see what developers
build on top of this platform.
The Androidwear SDK
enables you to build
glanceable, contextual apps for
this new category of device.
Let's talk through
the capabilities
it gives to developers.
And then we'll
show some examples.
Right off the bat, Androidwear
automatically bridges
notifications from
your Android phone
or tablet directly
to your watch.
Now, Android's
notification APIs already
allow you to build
beautiful user interfaces
with big pictures,
actions, and more.
And there are
hundreds of thousands
of apps delivering billions of
these notifications every day.
And now, they're
available on your wrist.
Back in March, we released a
developer preview, enabling
apps running on the phone to
add things like voice replies,
have several pages, and group
notifications in bundles.
With these additions,
you can begin
to provide a tailored
experience for wearables.
And we've used these
features to add wear support
to Google apps, like
Hangouts and Gmail.
And there's been a huge
response from developers.
The very best wearable apps
respond to the user's context,
put glancable cards
in the stream,
and allow the user
to take direct action
in just a few seconds.
Here's one of my
favorite examples.
With Pinterest, you can
follow other people's pins.
Pinterest app will let you know
when you're near a place that's
being pinned by
someone you follow.
So Jeff's friend Susie
loves Korean barbecue.
And she's somewhat
of an authority
on the best restaurants
in San Francisco.
So when Jeff is in
the city, Pinterest
can notify him
that he's near one
of Susie's pinned restaurants.
The notification will appear
on his wrist just like this.
And it uses pages, allowing
him to quickly glance
at the details, then
swipe to see a map.
And if he like it, he can
start navigation right
from his wrist.
This is using Google
Maps for mobile,
which gives you turn by turn
directions on your watch.
It's particularly useful
when you're walking.
And it works with all
Android Wear devices.
In addition to what's possible
with notifications bridged
from the phone, today we're
making a full Android Wear
SDK available which
enables you to write
code-- It's pretty great.
It enables you to write
code that runs directly
on the wearable itself.
And almost all the API's
that you're already
familiar with on Android
are available here.
That means that you can
present fully customized UI,
read sensors directly,
and much, much more.
We're also introducing a new
set of API's and Google Play
services that makes
it easy for your app
to send data between a phone
or tablet and a wearable.
And we've road tested these
API's with some developers
over the past few weeks.
Let's take a look at
examples of what they built.
Eat 24 is an app that makes
food ordering both fun and easy.
Now watch this.
Hopefully I'm going to
order a pizza in 20 seconds.
When it comes to take out,
I'm a creature of habit.
And Eat 24 has
recognized this and takes
advantage of that
contextual stream.
Around the same time I
made an order last week
it puts a notification
suggesting I order again.
I can tap on the
notification and launch
into their full screen UI.
And here I'm presented with
a beautiful interface that
lets me confirm the kind
of food I'd like today,
let's stick with pizza.
And then I can quickly swipe to
see and repeat my last order.
Just one more tap to pay,
and the pizza's on its way.
I think that clocked
in under 20 seconds.
Now you might be wondering
how this got to my watch.
Well all I had to do was
install the Eat 24 app
from the Play store on my phone.
When a watch is connected, the
wearable portion of the app
is automatically installed and
kept up to date on that watch.
I mentioned the
new wearable API's
for easy communication
between phone and watch.
All the Cooks is a social
recipes app which has made
really great use of these API's.
I don't know about you,
but I find it really hard
to follow recipes,
especially when
it gets to those tricky
bits where everything's
happening at the same time.
So wouldn't it be more
convenient if I could just
look down at my watch
and see what to do next?
With the All the Cooks
app I can choose a recipe.
Let's go into my favorites and
choose this beef brisket chili.
The recipe will immediately
appear on my watch.
So it's always
right there with me.
Let's get started.
I've got all the
ingredients, so let's start
following the steps.
Now watch the phone carefully.
As I move from step to step,
the phone stays in sync too.
And if you're wondering
whether or not
it's safe to wear your
watch while cooking,
it's great to know that
all the devices we're
talking about today
are water resistant.
And with All the Cooks, whenever
a recipe calls for a timer,
like this four
hours in the oven,
I can do that right
away on my wrist.
So no more burnt dinner.
We saw some great examples of
voice actions earlier today.
And we believe
voice actions will
be most useful when
they can invoke
the best service in any app.
We're just getting
started with this,
but we're making voice
available for some key actions
on the wearable today
and we'll be adding more
over the coming months.
Lift is a transportation
service and ride sharing
app that allows you
to request a car
to pick you up at
your exact location.
Lift have implemented
our call a car intent.
So it's really easy to just walk
outside and say, "OK, Google,
call me a car."
You'll see that Lift is able to
determine Jeff's exact location
from his phone an
presents this confirmation
screen so he can
verify his address.
The app is also made great use
of notifications in the stream.
You can see when
your car has arrived,
keep up to date throughout
the journey, and even rate
your driver right
from your wrist
when you're at your destination.
Thanks to all our developers.
Now, we showed a
preview of a couple of
watched we were working on with
our partners back in March.
The LGG watch will
be available to order
later today on the Play store.
In addition, you
might have caught
a glimpse of a new
device during the demos.
We're very happy that Samsung
is joining the Android wear
family with the
Samsung Gear Live.
And the Samsung
Gear Live is also
available to order later today.
The Moto 360 is the first watch
to adopt the round Android Wear
UI.
And it will be available
for sale later this summer.
Those are just the
first three watches.
There are many more
on the way, and we're
thrilled to enable
developers across the world
to build apps for
what we believe
will be a revolutionary
new form factor.
And now, I'd like to invite
Patrick Brady on stage
to tell you about how we're
bringing Android to the car.