Design is essential
in today's world.
It defines your experiences
and your emotions.
So we challenged ourselves to
create a design that was not
just for Android
phones and tablets.
We worked together-- Android,
Chrome, and across all
of Google-- to craft
one consistent vision
for mobile, desktop, and beyond.
We wanted a design that
was clear and simple,
and that people would
intuitively understand.
So we imagined, what
if pixels didn't just
have color, but also depth?
What if there was an
intelligent material that
was as simple as paper but
could transform and change
shape in response to touch?
And this led us to
a way of thinking
that we call material design.
[APPLAUSE]
We drew inspiration
from paper and ink.
However, unlike real
paper, our digital material
can expand, reform, and
reshape intelligently.
The material has physical
surfaces and edges
because the human mind is wired
at its most primitive level
to instinctively
understand objects
and their relationships.
Those scenes and
shadows provide meaning
about what you can touch
and how it will move.
In the real world, every small
change in position and depth
creates subtle but
important changes
in lighting and shadows.
So as part of the L preview,
we'll now allow app developers
to specify an elevation
value for any UI surface,
and the framework will render
it in correct perspective
with virtual light sources
and real time shadows.
[APPLAUSE]
Material design is
beautiful and bold
because clean,
typographical layouts
are simple and
easy to understand.
Your content is the focus.
So the L preview will
allow app developers
to easily colorize all
framework elements in your app
to match the theme
to your brand.
And we're previewing
a new support library
that we call Palette to easily
extract colors from images
and really put those vivid
pictures front and center.
We're giving designers familiar
tools like baseline grids
that work across screens.
Grids ensure apps have
a consistent rhythm
and character, and
this will allow
you to start with a
design on a phone,
and logically and easily bring
that same design to tablets
and laptops.
Now, one design doesn't
mean one size fits all.
Our guidelines allow you to
appropriately adapt the UI,
so your users will already
know their way around your app
no matter what
screen they use it
on And we've also updated
our system font, Roboto,
so that designers and developers
can use one type face designed
and optimized for every screen,
from your watch to your laptop
to your television.
So now let's talk
about animation.
It's delightful when your
touch is rewarded with motion,
and material
surfaces slide around
with the physics of
card stock, but they
respond to touch with
splashes of virtual ink
that are like ripples in a pond.
As part of the L preview, all of
your application's UI building
blocks have been updated to
include rich, animated touch
feedback.
[APPLAUSE]
And no detail is too small to
bring a smile to your face,
like when the reload button
loops around or the playback
controls can change.
Finally, in the real world,
nothing teleports from one
place to another, and
that's why it's so important
to animate every
change on screen
in a way that makes sense.
In the L preview,
Android developers
will now be able to
create seamless animations
from any screen to any other
between activities, and even
between apps.
[APPLAUSE]
So you're probably wondering
how this looks like in practice.
We're going to give
you a sneak peak at one
of our familiar
Google applications
in the new material design.
Here you can see,
step by step, how
we update the design--
the typography,
the grid changes, and finally,
the surfaces and bold colors.
And a few small changes make
a really big difference.
And you can also
see how easy it is
to take that same design
to different screens.
Now, I've talked
about only a few
of the highlights of
material design and just some
of the APIs that you can try
out in the Android L preview.
But as we all know, people
spend an enormous amount of time
on the web, and
especially the mobile web.
Last year at I/O, we
announced Polymer,
which was a powerful new
UI library for the web.
Today, we're bringing you
all of the material design
capabilities to the
web through Polymer.
As a web developer, you'll
be able to build applications
out of material
design building blocks
with all of the same
surfaces, bold graphics,
and smooth animations
at 60 frames per second.
So between the L
preview and Polymer,
you can bring the same
rich, fluid material design
to every screen.
And to help you take full
advantage of this framework,
we've also completely
redesigned and created
one unified set of style
guidelines for every screen
and for all devices.
These guidelines will help
designers and developers
alike understand best
practices and build
consistent, beautiful
experiences.
We're releasing the first draft
of these guidelines as part
of our preview today
at google.com/design.
[APPLAUSE]